this is a blockchain demo we're going to
do this in a very visual way though I'm
going to make it very easy to understand
by stepping through the key pieces of
what a blockchain is in a visual way but
before we get started we need to take a
look at this thing that we call a
sha-256 hash okay and a hash this is
this is one of them right here
hash looks like a bunch of random
numbers and essentially what it is it's
a fingerprint of some digital data and
it just so happens it's the fingerprint
of whatever I type in this box so if I
type my name on theirs into this box you
see that the hash has changed matter of
fact it changed every time I typed a
letter right so I'm going to go back to
so it says onder's okay so this is a the
hash of the name onder's all lowercase
it starts with one 9ea right okay so if
I delete that and I go again type
onder's again you can see it starts with
one 9ei the same exact hash in that
sense it's a digital fingerprint of this
data whatever data is here every time
you type exactly the same data you get
exactly the same hash and I can type
anything I want so you can have nothing
like this you know III b0 that's that's
the hash of nothing or you could type
tons and tons of stuff a matter of fact
you could put like the Library of
Congress in here and you would get a
hash and the interesting thing about it
is regardless of there if there's a tiny
amount of information no information or
the entire Library of Congress you're
always going to get a hash that is this
long this many characters are you're not
going to be able to pre guess what this
is you kind of have to put the Library
of Congress in here to figure out what
the hash is but you you always get
exactly the same hash regardless of how
many times you put exactly the same
information in so what I'm going to do
is extend this idea of a hash into
something that we're going to call a
block alright so let's take a look at a
block so this is a block and it's
exactly like the hash it's just that
that data section I've broken out now
into three sections one called block
this is just some kind of a number this
is block number one on nonce which is
just yet another number we'll go into
what that is in a second and then just
some more data just very similarly to
the way that we had it before
however the hash of this which includes
all of this information up here is down
here and it begins with four zeros you
see that it's a relatively unusual hash
you know most of them are not really
going to start with four zeros like that
but this one happens to and because it
does totally arbitrarily I'm going to
say that this block is signed okay so
what would happen if I were to change
any one piece of this information let's
say if I were to type something here
right the hash is going to change and
what's a chance of if I type letters
this hash is going to start with four
zeros pretty low it's probably not right
so let's see what happens when I do that
I'm just going to say hi oh look at that
write this hash does not start with four
zeros and so the big background here is
turned red so now you know that this
this block with this information in it
is not a valid or assigned block okay
and that's where this nonce comes in
this nonce is just a number that you can
set to try to find a number that fits so
that this hash starts with four zeros
again all right so how do we do that
well let's start with one does that
start with no it's three two so that's
not one so let's try to FF no three four
five so actually get the idea like I
could sit here oh there's one that
starts with a zero I could sit here all
day typing these numbers and trying to
figure out one that actually is going to
hash out to something that starts with
four zeros going to take a long time so
here I have my little mind but
I'm sure you've been wondering what
happens if I press that so what's going
to happen when I press this mine button
is it's going to run through all the
numbers from 1 all the way up to try to
find one where the hash starts with 4
zeros in this process is called mine
let's do it right now so now it's
checking all of the numbers from 1 all
the way up look there now it's stopped
at 59,000 396 and that one just happens
to hash out to something that starts
with 4 zeros and it satisfies my little
definition of what a signed block is ok
so that's that's a block now can you
tell me what a block chain is it's
probably just a chain of these blocks
well how do you how do you put them
together let's let's do that all right
so here's my block chain I've blocked
number one it has some kind of announced
just like before there's some data area
to it but then it has this previous here
it's a bunch of zeros let's let's roll
forward so this is block 2 and block 3
and for this block chain has 5 blocks on
it right the previous here starts with 0
0 a e8 right is this number a e8 and
then this previous you know B 9 0 is
this one over here B 9 0 so you can see
that each block points backwards to the
one before it and you remember that that
first block over here there actually is
no previous so it's just a bunch of
zeros it's actually just a fake number
ok so just like we did before what
happens if I change some information
here right it's going to change the hash
of this block and it's going to
invalidate it right well let's try that
so I'm going to type PI again sure
enough that block is invalid all right
just as we assumed but what would happen
I'm going to fix that now we'll go back
to something that worked what would
happen if I change something in this
block right it's going to change this
hash but this hash gets copied up too
this previous so it's going to it's
going to change this one too right so it
should break both blocks so let me try
typing hi in there and sure enough all
right so we can go back as far as we
want you know to some point in the in
the past and break that block and it'll
break all the blocks since then
everything before is still green but
this one is is red it's so if I wanted
to you know change something in this
this block chain I could just go over to
block number five right here we could
change it I'll put hi and then we could
remind it you know and pick a different
knots we'll do that right now and we
could essentially alter the chain so
we've done it so that we should be good
down right alright well what happens if
I go back in time to here and I break it
here now I have to mine this block which
will pick a nonce that makes this block
hash out to four zeros if we can find
one sometimes it takes a while because
it's got to run through a lot of them
there it is it found one at a hundred
and thirty eight thousand all right but
this one is still broken because
although this one starts with four zeros
adding the four zeros with different
stuff up here still makes this block
hash out incorrectly so I also have to
mine this block all right and that takes
some amount of time that one was a
little bit quicker and then I have to
mine this block to fix it all right so
what we're showing here is that if I go
and change this last block all I have to
do is remind this block if I go way back
in time to back here and I make a change
like that I'm going to have to mine this
one this one this one and this one so
the more blocks that go by the more
blocks in the past that we are the
harder and harder and harder it is to
make a change and so that's how a block
chain is going to resist
mutation resist change okay so now you
like like you know I did if I if if I do
this in this block here you can see that
I've changed it to hi and a remind at
blah blah blah how would I know that my
block chain has been remind alright
let's take a look at that I'm going to
hit this little distributed thing so now
we have a just distributed block chain
it looks exactly like the last block
chain okay up to five the but this is
pure a the first peer if we go down here
you can see here's P or B and it happens
to have an exact copy of the blockchain
there's actually also a P or C down here
right and this could go on forever
there's many many peers out on the
internet and they all have a complete
copy of the blockchain so in this case
if I look at this hash it's 0 e for be
alright if I go down to this one I
notice it also has a for B if I go down
to this last one it has a for B so they
must be identical and I'm going to
demonstrate that by going here
and typing something I'll type hi again
and then I will remind this block I've
got some other number now let's put some
other number up here so I should be able
to mine this block okay now all the
chains are green right they're all green
however this chain says the last hash is
efore B the bottom one says that to e
for B and this middle one here says for
CAE so I know just by glancing at this
one little hash that something is wrong
in this block chain even though all of
the hashes start with four zeros I know
that this one is different and it's
different because I have two it's
essentially two against one we're a
little democracy here right this guy
argues that it's efore be this guy
argues that it's four ce4
CA and this one is e for B so e for B
wins so that's how a completely
distributed copy having a copy on many
different computers they can all very
quickly see if all of the blocks are
identical and remember block chains can
have you know four or five hundred
thousand blocks very easily so rather
than checking through all of them all
you really have to do is look at the
hash of the most recent one and you can
see that if anything in the past
anything way back here was altered you
can tell by looking at this at the last
block in this in the chain you know it's
going to hash out to something that
doesn't start with four zeros and looks
very different from what the hash is on
the the good chains are okay so that's a
block chain that's the entire thing
there is no more to it than that but
it's kind of not really useful because
we don't have some something in this
data area that means anything I keep
typing my name or hi and it's kind of
that's sort of irrelevant information so
what we really want is a token so let's
do a token on our blockchain all right
now look at this so I have this token
just totally arbitrarily I'm calling
these I guess dollars right so we have
25 dollars from Darcy to Bingley four
dollars and twenty seven cents go from
Elizabeth to Jane you get the idea it's
basically there's all these transactions
that are happening and I've just
replaced the data with these
transactions and just like we saw before
you know so there's multiple blocks here
this one has more transit it doesn't
matter how many transactions there are
there can be many or they can be few or
none if we keep going forward in here
just like we saw before if we go down
and we notice we have all these other
copies of the same blockchain right so
now here's where the immutability is
important if I change something back
here you'll notice that this is you know
a 7fc blah blah blah it's something it's
something else
so it's something different than what's
down here so in in this way I mean it's
very important that if I were to go back
in time and change some value that we
would notice it's it's very important
with money that you don't lose track and
that's the whole point of using a
blockchain here this is a whole point of
resisting any kind of modifications you
know of things that have happened in the
past so that's the that's the reasoning
behind having using a blockchain to
remember tokens now one thing I would
mention here is that we're not listing
you know Darcy has $100 and he's giving
25 of it to Bingley the only thing we're
saying is Darcy
gives 25 to Bingley we're not
remembering a bank account balance we're
only remembering money movements so this
begs the question does Darcy have 25
dollars well we have a problem here in
this version of the blockchain we don't
actually know if Darcy has 25 dollars so
let's look at a coinbase transaction so
if we look back here a coin base we're
going to add a coinbase transaction to
our blocks and this is this is very
similar to what we've seen before but
we've just adding a coin base at the top
and what's that that what that's saying
is we're going to invent a hundred
dollars out of thin air and give it to
anders and there's no transactions in
this block because nobody had any money
previous to this in the next block
another hundred dollars comes out of
nowhere and goes to honors i'm a fan i
love it right i'll take 100 bucks now we
have some transactions you can see that
they're all from onder's they're all for
me because i'm the only one who has any
money at this point so i'm sending ten
of my dollars to Sophie do I have ten
dollars yeah I do I look back and I see
that this coinbase transaction has given
me a hundred so I have at least ten and
I can send it on and you add all these
up and they don't go over a hundred and
it follows sort of a basic rule
of a currency like you can't invent it
out of thin air you can't create money
out of thin air you it's it's dispersion
is controlled so now if we look at this
blockchain that we've created and we zip
forward in time and we notice that we
see that Jackson is giving Alexa two
dollars and so does Jackson actually
have two dollars to give Alexa well we
go back a block before and we see that
Emily who had gotten ten dollars from
onder's gave ten to Jackson and so
Jackson does have the money so we can
just go backwards and and find that out
that's actually one of the benefits of
having a previous here it's easy to go
backwards we we just look for the block
that looks like that that has that hash
and here it is right here right so you
points two blocks back in time and
allows us to trace the provenance of any
coin that we want so that's a basic
blockchain and we're running a currency
on top of it and as you know block
chains are there many copies everybody
has a copy of it so if we mutate you
know this and make it six dollars these
go invalid it does not agree with with
these block chains down here these
copies of the same blockchain down here
so this resists tampering which is what
you want for a currency it works very
well for things that are small and
transactional like like this go ahead
and fix that and there they're of just a
very efficient way to handle agreement
on what has happened in the past it's
kind of this immutable history that that
goes goes down with time so that's a
basic blockchain and a token on it there
we're glossing over some main points but
if you dig into the demo and and click
through these things and play around
with it you'd get a better and better
idea of how this works there will be a
part two where we go into a little bit
more
detail about how the transactions are
created till then